And so here we are at the home page for modal.
Modal의 홈페이지에 나와 있어요
At modal.com spelt model not not model which is confusing.
모달로요 모델은 모델이지 헷갈리네요
So what is modal.
그럼 모듈이란 무엇일까요?
So modal is a service that allows you to take code.
Modal은 코드를 취할 수 있게 해주는 서비스예요
And it really can be any code and deploy it and run it remotely so that you can run it from, say,
어떤 코드든 원격으로 배포할 수 있습니다 주피터랩이나 파이썬
JupyterLab or just from some Python code running on your box.
코드로 실행할 수 있도록요
And what makes modal so powerful is that it makes it incredibly easy just to wrap up a function and
Modal이 강력한 이유는 함수를 정리하고 호출하는 게 아주 쉬워 거의
have that be called so that it's almost transparent to you.
투명하게 보인다는 거죠
It almost feels like you're calling a function that's running locally on your box.
박스에 로컬로 실행되는 함수를 호출하는 것 같아요
And in fact, it's been called out to the cloud.
사실 클라우드에 호출이 왔어요
And the answer is coming back.
답이 돌아오고 있어요
So it gives you such transparency, and it allows you to work almost seamlessly between your box and
투명성을 제공하고 박스와 클라우드 사이에서 거의 매끄럽게 작업할 수 있게
the cloud.
해주죠
Now, a lot of the way it works is that it also allows you to package your code into an API, and have
작동 원리의 대부분은 API에 코드를 패키지할 수 있게 해주는 겁니다 사람들이
it running in such a way that people can use like Rest APIs to to call your code.
REST API 같은 걸 이용해 코드를 호출할 수 있도록요
We're not going to do that because we're working in Python.
파이썬 으로 작업하고 있으니 그렇게 하지 않을 거예요
And this is all Python code.
파이썬 으로 된 코드죠
And it's even easier if all you need to do is call Python functions remotely on the cloud.
클라우드에서 원격으로 파이썬 함수를 호출하는 것이 더 쉽고요
Um, and whilst it is, as I say, mostly used by AI teams and for for AI as it's, as it's showing
인공지능 팀에서 주로 사용하고 인공지능을 위한 건데 여기서 보시다시피 인공지능과
right here AI and data and machine learning.
데이터 머신 러닝이죠
Um, it can also just be used for really any anything that you can write in Python, you can run on
파이썬 으로 작성할 수 있는 모든 것에 사용될 수 있습니다 클라우드에서 실행할 수도
the cloud.
있고요
Um, and so it's um, it's it's very versatile indeed.
그래서 아주 다재다능해요
One other thing I'll mention that makes it very powerful is that you only pay for the compute time that
아주 강력하게 만드는 또 다른 것은 사용하는 컴퓨팅 시간에만 돈을
you use, unlike services like, like, uh, you know, AWS or something.
지불한다는 겁니다 AWS 같은 서비스와는 다르죠
Um, it's one of these, these things where it will spin up a server on demand, and if it's not used
주문형 서버를 스핀업 하는데 한동안 사용하지 않으면
for a while, it will, it will, it will, uh, pause that server and you'll only pay for the CPU minutes
서버를 일시 정지하고 서버가 실행 중인 CPU분만 지불하게
that your server is running for.
되죠
So, uh, also the good news is that if you sign up for a new account, you get $30 of free credit,
또 좋은 소식은 새 계좌를 개설하시면 30달러의 무료 카드가 제공되는데 우린 그 30달러를
and we won't even come close to spending that $30.
쓸 일이 없다는 거죠 Get it
In this class.
이 수업에서요
So you don't need to be concerned about about charges.
그러니 기소 같은 건 걱정 안 해도 돼요
This will be a freebie should you get addicted and you end up using modal for all sorts of purposes,
만약 중독되어서 모든 모듈을 사용하게 된다면, 무료로 제공해드릴 수 있습니다. 만약 사용하게 되더라도
then I can't be held accountable for that.
저는 책임지지 않을 거예요.
But you will get hopefully your $30 of, uh, free credits unless they take that away.
그래도 30달러짜리 크레딧은 받을 수 있을 거예요 get get get이 취소되지 않는다면요
But even if they do that, as you will see, it's not exactly an expensive proposition.
하지만 그렇게 해도 보시다시피 그리 비싼 제안은 아니에요
So when you go to modal comm, you'll need to sign up the first time and create an account if assuming
Modalcom에 가면 처음 등록하고 계정을 만들어야 해요 이미 없다고
you don't have one already.
가정하면요
And once you've done that, you'll end up in a dashboard.
그렇게 하면 대시보드에 나오죠
And this is my dashboard right here.
이게 제 대시보드예요
Um, and you can see here my live usage, um, in the time that I've been using modal to prepare for
여기 제 라이브 사용이 보이시죠 이 수업을 준비하기 위해 Modal을 사용했는데
this class that has been going on for a while and running it a number of times, I've managed to rack
시간이 좀 걸렸고 여러 번 실행했어요 무료 신용카드
up a $5 bill, uh, out of my $30 of free credit.
30달러에서 5달러가 모였네요
So I've barely scratched the surface, and even if I hadn't got the free credit, it would be a $5 price
아직 수박 겉핥기 수준인데 무료 크레딧이 아니라도 지금까지 한 일에 5달러가
tag for everything I've done so far.
드는 거예요
So, as I say, it's it's cheap.
그래서 싸게 먹히는 거죠
Um, here I'm looking at at apps, which are the programs that I've deployed.
제가 배포한 프로그램인 앱을 보고 있는데요
And of course we're going to be building a pricer service later.
물론 나중에 가격 서비스도 구축할 거예요
And if I go into this, you'll see that you can see all the different deployments that I've made of
여기로 가면 이 서비스에 대해 만든 다양한 배포가 보이시죠
And this will all make more sense when we actually do it.
실제로 해보면 이해가 더 잘 될 거예요
And you can see it's been called apparently 116 times.
보다시피 116번이나 호출됐어요
Uh, and you can see various other things about it.
다른 것들도 볼 수 있어요
Um, but really, that's it.
하지만 그게 다예요
The one of the nice things about modal is that whilst one does have tokens and keys and all the rest
방식의 장점 중 하나는 토큰과 키 등 모든 게 있지만 여러분이 가서 설정하고
of it, you don't need to go in and set it up and write it down because it's going to do it all for
적을 필요가 없다는 거죠 여러분이 다 알아서 할 테니까요 아주
you and it's going to be very easy.
쉬워요 REST
All you have to do is sign up with an account and then everything else will come.
계정만 하나 만들면 나머지는 알아서 다 들어와요
Will will follow naturally.
윌도 자연스럽게 따라올 거예요
Okay, so with that, once you've signed up with your modal account, do some clicking around.
자, 모듈 계정에 등록하고 나면 클릭을 좀 하세요
You can always read the there's there's really nice docs.
항상 읽을 수 있어요 정말 좋은 문서들이 있어요
There's this this guide.
이 가이드가 있어요
You don't need to read this because we'll be doing some of this.
이걸 할 거니까 읽을 필요 없어요
But it gives you a real sense.
하지만 진짜 느낌이 오죠
There's a hello World program as well, but we'll be doing that ourselves as you will see.
Hello World 프로그램도 있는데 그건 저희가 직접 할 거예요
We'll get to that in the next video.
Get it은 다음 비디오에서 알려드릴게요
I will see you then.
그때 봐요